Marry me.
Excuse me?
I have this really annoying
work party next Saturday.
Oh. I can't go.
But it's compulsory.
For you. maybe.
What would you normally
be doing on a Saturday night?
Maybe watching TV with my grandparents.
Are you right?
Yeah. yeah.
Ryan. this is my boss. Nat.
Why did I call you David?
Really nervous.
I thought they'd be drinking
and mingling by now.
We need a distraction.
No. I'm not drinking.
Oh. really?
Well Nat says 'Cheers.'
Oh. no. no.
That's from Antonio.
He says 'Cheers.'
You read them perfectly.
Can you read me?
What do I need?
Are you okay?
I have a boyfriend.
I'm sorry.
I should have told you.
It's okay.
Did you buy this or did I?
You can have it.
No. I'd just end up throwing it away.
I've got to start again as a bachelor.
I don't want this place to smell
like a pathetic sex lair. do I.
Chuck it then.
I hate incense.
And so do I.
Wait.
So we're burning this for no reason?
I thought you liked it.
Wow.
So our apartment's smelled like sandalwood
for two years out of politeness. hey?
I guess we didn't really know each other
after all. did we?
David. I'm so sorry.
Oh. Em. I'm just joking.
Hey. you know. um.
you know Jen from my work.
Uh. yeah.
Yeah. little short Jen.
Um... I fucked her.
What?
When?
It was once at the Christmas party.
There was a couple of times in the
break room as well.
More than once.
Yeah. like five or six times.
Six.
You make me feel like
absolute shit for the past week.
and you've been having
a fucking affair this whole time?
I'm not having an affair!
No. we weren't sneaking around
and meeting up.
We just fucked every now and then.
to let off some steam.
What. and then you just come home
and act like everything was fine?
Everything was fine.
I love you.
Listen. me and her.
we didn't have any chemistry
or anything like that.
it was just... We got it on.
You know how hectic everything
can get at my work sometimes. right?
Sometimes you need a release.
I guess she just really likes to fuck.
Can you please stop saying
fucked and fucking?
That's all it was.
Em. I'm doing this to let you off the hook.
See. this is why I didn't tell you
because I knew you'd be hurt.
Well. you could have
avoided that by not sticking
your dick in some fucking
random nurse six times.
Shh.
Come on. we hadn't had sex
in almost a year.
Oh. it's all my fault.
I didn't say that.
You literally just did.
Nope.
So you were fucking this nurse
because what?
I didn't feel like it.
I didn't say that. Don't twist it.
I'm not blaming you.
I just want to
give you context. that's all.
Context?
You know. this isn't a thesis
or a dissertation. David.
I don't need footnotes
on why you're a cunt.
Hey!
Hey. I may have fucked someone.
yes. I did.
but you had an emotional relationship
with someone and you fucked them.
That's a pretty big deal to me.
We both did what we did.
It's not a competition about
who's the biggest arsehole. is it?
Spoiler alert. it's you.
I didn't tell you to hurt you.
I just don't want you
to go around hurting yourself.
You can hate me all you like.
I mean. I don't hate you.
Well. I do hate you.
How long have you been
sitting out here for?
About two and a half cigarettes.
I have to finish it.
they're really fucking expensive.
You're a grand human being.
Am I?
I'm sorry.
I just... I came here to say I'm so sorry
for involving you in all this shit.
That's a lot of sorrys.
I only smoke when I'm stressed.
And I know it's gross.
and I'm going to quit.
The irony is if I cough up a lung.
I'm going to end up in the ER.
and then I'm going
to have to see David again.
so. yeah. I really should quit.
So it didn't go well then?
Well. I've got all my shit in the back
of my car. so... as well as expected.
Where are you going?
I don't know.
You know. you could've just told me.
If it makes you feel better.
he was fucking some nurse for months.
You came prepared.
I'm gross. but I'm not a complete arsehole.
Yeah. I didn't think that part through.
I should go.
What are you doing out here?
You can't stay out here all day.
Come on. sort it out inside.
I...
Come on. she'll be offended if you don't.
Emily. this is my Nan. Lorna.
Hello. Emily.
Come on in.
You're much prettier
when you're not carrying your shoes
up the stairs at 3am.
Did he tell you we're having
a bit of a party?
No. he did not.
It's my 50th.
Not my birthday. Anniversary.
I'm a little bit older than 50.
I'll tell you who's going
to be very excited to see you.
Morgan?
This is Emily.
This is Morgan.
Nice to meet you. Emily.
Nice to meet you.
Happy anniversary.
Oh. thank you.
Look. Emily. help yourself to drinks
in the kitchen.
And baby boy.
will you get us some music?
Yeah.
Come on.
Oh. Ian.
Congratulations.
Baby boy. huh?
That's cute.
Yeah.
Wow.
Did we walk all the way back to the 1980s?
Yeah.
This was my mum's room.
Huh. See. those are good parents.
My mum turned my bedroom into a sewing room
while I was still moving my things out.
Is she any good at it?
Fuck no.
It's been many rooms since then.
Think of any white woman hobby.
and I guarantee it's been
in that room at least once.
Scrapbooking. quilting...
You know it.
Last time I was there.
it was an interior design studio.
I think she thinks having kids
held her back from her true calling.
What are we working with here?
Ahh.
I see where you get your taste from.
Nothing here past 1992.
Oh. there you are.
You came.
Of course.
Any excuse for a few wines?
Em. this is Ellen.
She's my work friend.
Hi.
Work friend?
Listen to him.
He makes it sound like I'm a
25-year-old intern or something.
So. how do you know the family?
Oh. Lorna and I know each other from
the Salvation Army volunteer weekends.
I got Ryan his interview
at the firm we work at.
Sorry.
Do you mind. I'll...
I'll be back.
Yeah.
Do you still want these? Under the couch.
Not mine.
What the fuck?
She seems nice.
Yeah. she is.
But?
But it's complicated.
You're a forensic accountant.
You deal with complicated everyday.
Yeah. but this is different.
Something's only complicated
until you understand it.
Go put some music on.
Oh. thanks.
No!
Not hers. I swear.
If they're not yours. I don't know whose.
I haven't seen you in a while.
I want to put on
'Girls just want to have fun.'
Do you remember that?
I remember that when it came out.
Hey. thanks so much for coming.
Thanks for coming.
Enjoy.
I see you met Uncle Ian.
Great-uncle.
He's not bad. I wouldn't say great.
He makes it sound
like he's never said that one before.
You coming tomorrow?
Are you going to be up for it?
I'm always up for it. It's my job.
This is mid-strength.
And you can blame this lovely girl.
You should bring her along.
It wouldn't make much of a date.
Where are we going?
Uncle Ian is Reverand Ian
at the Uniting Church.
Oh. my gosh.
I have just been swearing at you
this whole time.
I'm so sorry.
He doesn't give a shit.
It's true. I don't give a shit.
Don't worry.
he's not trying to convert you or anything.
But that's not true.
I try to convert everyone.
Wouldn't be much of a minister
if I didn't.
Well. I'll give you there's nothing
to convert me from.
I am the daughter of heathens.
Excellent.
All my most successful converts
have been heathens.
You okay?
Yes.
It was lovely to meet you.
It was lovely to meet you too.
She's... interesting.
She is.
Wait!
Those undies are mine.
I forgot.
You look a little bit lost.
I'm just really not used
to these family things.
You don't have family?
I do.
Just not like this.
It's okay to feel lost.
I mean. it's not comfortable.
but. you know.
sometimes it clears the path
for new things to happen.
I was with someone else when I met him.
Really?
Mmm. mmm.
I mean. life rarely gives you what you want
when you actually want it.
What happened?
Ha.
Oh.
Drama and heartache.
But what's the alternative
when you feel something so strongly?
You know. one of the best things
about getting older?
You realise that the things
you worry about now
aren't going to matter in the future.
...on lunch break and you make a cup of tea. and...
Speeches!
Speeches. everybody!
Hey. guys.
I just want to welcome you to Morgan and
Lorna's 50th wedding anniversary.
I know some of you have come a long way.
Some from Victoria. New South Wales.
Jim and Kate. coming down from Townsville.
the three-day drive.
Thank you.
All the rest of you
drove about five or ten minutes
which is not nearly as impressive.
But I. myself. just wandered up from
underneath the house.
When I was born. Morgan and Lorna
had already been married for 16 years.
And they've been married my whole life.
And I can't imagine it any other way.
They do everything together.
Literally.
Pop will go with Nan to the shops.
He'll just sit on the couch outside KMart
and wait for her to do her thing.
Has nothing to do. hates shopping.
but he'll just sit there and wait.
even before he had a phone to scroll on.
I remember when I was about nine or ten.
and I was sitting with him on the couch
waiting for what seemed like hours.
and I wanted to go to the bookstore. or
to the shoe shop. or... I can't remember.
And he said. no. he wouldn't let me go.
This is where she knows we are.
This is where we're going to wait.
And now he does have a phone.
And if he wanted to. he could wander off
and do his own thing
and call her or something.
But he doesn't.
He just sits there and tags her
in a couple of dozen Facebook posts and
dirty memes.
And then she gets home later that night
and hearts every single one of them
to let him know that she's seen them.
When they first met. they'd known each
other from around the traps
but never talked.
And then one day at a working bee.
Pop was on lunch
and he was making a cup of tea.
and he decided to make Nan one.
and she said 'Thank you'
and they started chatting.
And by the end of the chat.
he'd asked her out on a date.
And two months later. they were married.
I don't think you've made
a cup of tea ever since. have you?
No.
Anyway.
Say some words. mate.
That was brilliant.
Thank you all for coming.
We don't usually celebrate this day.
but 50 years is a long time.
and we haven't had one of these since...
Well. you know. it's...
yeah. it's been a while.
um...
Don't really know what to say.
Oh. I guess I'd want to thank
my beautiful wife for putting up with me.
Thank you. Lorna.
Yeah. thank you for coming.
It means a lot.
So. um. have a drink for us. and
if you can have one for Nora too...
Yeah.
Yeah. all right.
Thank you.
It was beautiful. darling.
Okay. to the cake.
Who wants to cut the cake?
She looks so young.
Well. she was young.
Fifteen there. that 's them together.
A week before her 16th birthday.
Wasn't ideal. of course.
But she was good with him.
Very sweet.
She had a beautiful voice. too.
Really?
Yeah. she sang in the choir.
Loudest one there.
Not a show-off. nothing like that. but
you just knew who it was coming from.
That's what I miss the most.
I used to sit in a chair in the afternoon
and hear her singing to him
when he was little.
She's the only one
who could put him to sleep.
Nobody else could.
Problem child.
No. no. no. no.
He was just like her. though.
They both picked up on the same things.
Both tuned to the same frequency
I think. but. ah...
he was better equipped for it. though.
She just got lost somewhere.
Don't know what went wrong.
I wish I did.
Oh. look. I'm sorry.
This is not a
very good introduction to us. is it?
What is?
Yeah. right. yeah.
That was a beautiful speech.
I'm sorry about your mum.
I had no idea.
Yeah.
She was 19 when she died.
She was in and out of trouble
and ended up dying of an overdose.
Did Nan tell you she was fifteen
when she had me?
She was a baby.
I wouldn't go that far.
Most 15-year-olds aren't out shoplifting
and partying and doing drugs.
whilst their baby is at home
with his stressed grandparents.
Do you know what happened?
She escaped rehab.
went missing for a couple of weeks.
Not like in the movies.
Just some random teen
camp out in the country.
They took her there a couple of times.
At first it was all good.
She was apparently very serious about
being responsible for a while.
And obviously that didn't stick.
The second time.
I guess she just couldn't take it.
Nan said she really
didn't want to go that time.
And so she jumped a fence
and took off one night.
They found her a couple of weeks later
in the city in some random house.
They said she probably died
a few days earlier.
That's awful.
Yeah.
Well...
Yeah. Nan told me once she felt like a
sense of relief in the end.
They'd been waiting years
for that phone call.
years of constant anxiety and worry. and
and then it was over.
and she was sad. of course. but relieved.
What about your grandpa?
I don't know.
I think we all
just remember her differently.
I should go.
I'd like you to stay.
I just want you to be happy.